<idea-plugin>
    <id>io.mp.sightline</id>
    <name>Sightline</name>
    <!-- No <version> here on purpose: build.gradle.kts is the single source and `patchPluginXml`
         writes it into the built descriptor. Two copies could disagree, and this one would win. -->
    <vendor email="support@cxk.co.za" url="https://cxk.co.za">Michael Carroll</vendor>

    <description><![CDATA[
        <p><b>Claude Code inside Android Studio, with visible project activity and controlled tool
        execution.</b></p>

        <p>
        Sightline provides a native Android Studio interface for a locally installed Claude Code CLI.
        </p>

        <p>Use it to:</p>
        <ul>
            <li>Chat with Claude without leaving Android Studio.</li>
            <li>Attach files and IDE context, and remove any of it before you send.</li>
            <li>Review tool requests and proposed changes as diffs before they apply.</li>
            <li>See files, commands, tests and relationships in the Activity Map.</li>
            <li>Inspect structured build, test and diagnostic results.</li>
        </ul>

        <p><b>Android-aware.</b> Sightline knows your build variant, connected device, module and
        running process, so you don't have to explain them. It reads Gradle failures into typed
        diagnoses, resolves crashes back to the line that threw, picks the tests worth running for
        what you changed, and audits your merged manifest. Logcat is redacted before it can reach a
        prompt.</p>

        <p><b>Requires the Claude Code CLI</b> (the <code>claude</code> command), installed and
        authenticated separately. Sightline does not provide Claude access, does not handle your
        credentials, and has no login screen or backend of its own.</p>

        <p><b>No telemetry.</b> No analytics, no usage statistics, nothing sent anywhere except to the
        local <code>claude</code> process you started. Your conversation is never written to disk.</p>

        <p>
        Sightline is an independent project and is not affiliated with or endorsed by Anthropic,
        JetBrains or Google. "Claude" and "Claude Code" are trademarks of Anthropic; "Android Studio"
        is a trademark of Google. Both are used only to describe compatibility.
        </p>

        <p>
        Copyright &#169; 2026 Michael Carroll. <b>Source-available</b> &#8212; the source is published so
        it can be read and audited, but it is not open source and may not be redistributed. Using
        Sightline in your work, including commercially, is expressly permitted. Free during the beta.
        See the licence accompanying this listing.
        </p>
    ]]></description>

    <change-notes><![CDATA[
        <p><b>0.1.0-beta</b> — first public release.</p>
        <ul>
            <li><b>Chat panel</b> — streaming replies, extended thinking, Markdown with syntax-highlighted
            code, collapsible tool cards, and edit diffs you review before they apply.</li>
            <li><b>Permission control</b> — five modes, inline Allow / Allow-always / Deny, a path guard
            that refuses credential locations outright, and a device gate that always confirms anything
            destroying app data.</li>
            <li><b>Agent Activity Map</b> — a live graph of what Claude is <i>observably</i> touching,
            with the evidence for every relationship it draws.</li>
            <li><b>Android control centre</b> — build-variant and device context supplied automatically,
            typed Gradle failure diagnosis, crash-to-source resolution, targeted test selection, redacted
            logcat, screen inspection, Compose and manifest analysis.</li>
            <li><b>No telemetry</b>, and no conversation persistence.</li>
        </ul>
        <p>This is a beta. Please report problems on the public issue tracker.</p>
    ]]></change-notes>

    <!-- Platform + Java module. Java support (always present in Android Studio) provides the PSI/UAST
         used for class-hierarchy enrichment (extends/implements). -->
    <depends>com.intellij.modules.platform</depends>
    <depends>com.intellij.modules.java</depends>

    <!-- Optional: Android Studio's own project model, for the one fact nothing else knows — the
         *currently selected* build variant. Everything else Android works without it (adb, the emulator
         binary, Gradle, and AGP's build output), so a plain IntelliJ IDEA loses a qualifier on a chip,
         not a feature. See docs/ANDROID.md §1.1. -->
    <depends optional="true" config-file="sightline-android.xml">org.jetbrains.android</depends>

    <extensionPoints>
        <!-- Implemented only from sightline-android.xml, so the implementation class never loads
             where its Android-Studio-internal imports can't resolve. -->
        <extensionPoint name="androidFactProvider" dynamic="true"
                        interface="io.mp.sightline.ide.android.AndroidStudioFactProvider"/>
    </extensionPoints>

    <extensions defaultExtensionNs="com.intellij">
        <toolWindow id="Sightline"
                    anchor="right"
                    factoryClass="io.mp.sightline.ClaudeToolWindowFactory"
                    icon="/icons/sightline.svg"/>
        <applicationService serviceImplementation="io.mp.sightline.settings.ClaudeSettings"/>
        <!-- Decouple approval/diff decisions from Swing so both the UI and the sandbox test bridge
             resolve them through the same logic. Plain classes, so registered here (not annotated). -->
        <projectService serviceImplementation="io.mp.sightline.ide.ApprovalCoordinator"/>
        <projectService serviceImplementation="io.mp.sightline.ide.DiffReviewCoordinator"/>
        <projectService serviceImplementation="io.mp.sightline.ide.QuestionCoordinator"/>
        <projectService serviceImplementation="io.mp.sightline.ui.SightlineUiState"/>
        <applicationConfigurable parentId="tools"
                                 id="io.mp.sightline.settings"
                                 displayName="Sightline"
                                 instance="io.mp.sightline.settings.ClaudeSettingsConfigurable"/>
    </extensions>
</idea-plugin>
